Charlie Haldane

Web Developer

Contact

Address Ottawa, ON, K1N 6V4

Phone 705 928 4783

E-mail xcdhaldane@gmail.com

Skills

Problem-Solving

Excellent

Written Communication

Excellent

Website Optimization

Very Good

Agile Workflow

Very Good

Software

HTML

Very Good

<u>Python</u>

Excellent

SQL

Very Good

CSS

Excellent

JavaScript

Excellent

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3 years of related experience. Specialized in React Framework and Python development.

Work History

2022-09 -Current

Pipeline TD

Monsters Aliens Robots Zombies VFX, Toronto, ON

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Integrated constructive programs into cohesive product.
- Generated a workflow pipeline for VFX artists to improve efficiency.
- Identified possible system enhancements to improving functionality and streamline administration.

2021-05 -Current

Full Stack Web Developer

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario

- Developed efficient and maintainable software according to business objectives and needs of clients.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Developed user interfaces for deployment on Amazon Web Services (AWS) platforms.
- Designed REST calls using React to streamline user interface performance.

2019-09 -2020-09

Automotive Installer

Canadian Tire, Peterborough, ON

- Performed diagnostic and troubleshooting procedures to find and identify root causes of mechanical issues.
- Inspected and tested vehicles and completed preventive maintenance such as engine tune-ups, oil changes, tire rotations, wheel balancing and filter replacement.
- Trained and coached junior employees on procedures for completing various types of repairs and maintenance on cars and light trucks.

Education

2020-09 -Current Bachelor's of Engineering: Software Engineering

University of Ottawa - Ottawa

2019-09 -2020-09 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Trent Univeristy - Peterborough

Certifications

2019-09

Canadian Armed Forces Certification of Service

References

Patrick Dumond, Professor, Univeristy of Ottawa (613)562-5800 - pdumond@uottawa.ca - Former Employer Jonathan Jeyes, Owner, Little Britain Auto (705) 344-9780 - jonathan.fastcar@yahoo.com - Former Employer Mana Azarm, Adjunct Professor, Berkeley (650) 467-9224 - Mazarm@uottawa.ca - Former Supervisor